Finding Aid for Center for Great Lakes and Aquatic Sciences (University of Michigan) records, 1945-2002.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Ship's Logs and Operations 1955-2002
  - Chief Scientist's Log
    - Mysis 1964-1970, 13 volumes in 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Naiad 1957-1964, 10 volumes in 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Halcyon 1955-1957, 1959, 6 volumes (Box 17)
    - Highland Lassie II 1965 (Box 17)
    - Lady Maggie 1961 (Box 17)
  - Chronological Files 1966-2002
    - 1966-1971 Grants Supporting Research Vessels, 3 folders (Box 38)
    - 1972-1974
      - Grants
        - Continuation of Support for Two Research Vessels (Box 38)
        - Ship Operations Support and Marine Technician Support (Box 38)
        - Support of Shipboard Technicians (Box 38)
      - Laurentian
        - Construction, F.B. Walker & Sons, Inc., 2 folders (Box 38)
        - License (Box 38)
    - 1975 Laurentian Construction (Box 38)
    - 1976 Laurentian Adjustments and Ships' Schedules (Box 38)
    - 1977 Ship Rates and Adjustments (Box 38)
    - 1978 Ship Rates and Use (Box 38)
    - 1980
      - Insurance (Box 38)
      - Operating Expenses (Box 38)
      - Ship Scheduling (Box 38)
    - 1981
      - Insurance (Box 38)
      - Schedules and Rates (Box 38)
    - 1982 Service Summaries (Box 38)
    - 1983
      - Laurentian Inspection (Box 38)
      - Mysis Rates (Box 38)
    - 1984 Rates, Budget, Funding, News Release (Box 38)
    - 1985
      - Charge Plans (Box 39)
      - Cruise Assessments (Box 39)
      - Cruise Reports (Box 39)
      - Grant: Oceanographic Instrumentation (Box 39)
      - Insurance (Box 39)
      - Laurentian
        - Repairs (Box 39)
        - Ship's Logs (Box 39)
      - Rates and Budget (Box 39)
      - Schedule (Box 39)
    - 1986
      - Budget and Billing (Box 39)
      - Correspondence (Box 39)
      - Cruise Assessments and Reports (Box 39)
      - Cruise Plans (Box 39)
      - Ship's Logs (Box 39)
    - 1987
      - Cruise Assessments and Reports (Box 39)
      - Cruise Profiles (Box 39)
      - Insurance (Box 39)
      - Rates and Budget (Box 39)
      - Requests for Ship Time (Box 39)
      - Schedule (Box 39)
      - Ship Facilities and Equipment (Box 39)
      - Ship's Logs (Box 39)
    - 1988
      - Cruise Plans (Box 39)
      - Insurance (Box 39)
      - Rates and Budget (Box 39)
      - Ship's Logs (Box 39)
    - 1989
      - Budget Summaries 1980-1989 (Box 39)
      - Cruise Plans (Box 39)
      - Cruise Reports (Box 39)
      - Equipment (Box 39)
      - Rates and Budget (Box 39)
      - Schedule (Box 39)
      - Ship's Logs (Box 39)
    - 1990
      - Cruise Reports (Box 39)
      - Insurance (Box 39)
      - Medical Supply Inventory (Box 39)
      - Proposals for Usage (Box 39)
      - Ship's Logs (Box 39)
    - 1991
      - Budget (Box 39)
      - Cruise Assessments and Reports (Box 39)
      - Cruise Plans (Box 39)
      - Ship's Logs (Box 39)
    - 1992
      - Budget (Box 39)
      - Captain's Reports, Cruise Assessments and Reports (Box 39)
      - Cruise Plans (Box 39)
      - Insurance (Box 39)
      - Laurentian Poem (Box 39)
      - Ship's Logs (Box 39)
      - Use Summaries 1986-1992 (Box 39)
    - 1993
      - Class Use (Box 39)
      - Correspondence (Box 39)
      - Cruise Assessments (Box 39)
      - Cruise Plans (Box 39)
      - Cruise Reports (Box 39)
      - Inspection Report (Box 39)
      - Insurance (Box 39)
      - Rates and Budget (Box 39)
      - Shared Use of Laurentian with National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) (Box 39)
      - Ship's Logs (Box 39)
    - 1994
      - Captain's Post Cruise Reports (Box 39)
      - Contact Information (Box 39)
      - Correspondence (Box 39)
      - Cruise Assessments (Box 39)
      - Cruise Plans (Box 39)
      - Cruise Reports (Box 39)
      - Insurance (Box 39)
      - Rates and Charge Sheets (Box 39)
      - Ship's Logs (Box 39)
    - 1995
      - Captain's Post Cruise Reports (Box 39)
      - Correspondence (Box 39)
      - Cruise Assessments (Box 39)
      - Cruise Plans (Box 39)
      - Cruise Reports (Box 39)
      - Insurance (Box 39)
      - Medical Supply Inventory (Box 39)
      - Rates and Charge Sheets (Box 39)
      - Ship's Logs (Box 40)
      - Support Grant (Box 40)
    - 1996
      - Captain's Post Cruise Reports (Box 40)
      - Cruise Assessments (Box 40)
      - Cruise Plans (Box 40)
      - Cruise Reports (Box 40)
      - Insurance (Box 40)
      - Rates and Budget (Box 40)
      - Ship Time Requests and Schedule (Box 40)
      - Ship's Logs (Box 40)
      - Support Grant (Box 40)
    - 1997
      - Captain's Post Cruise Reports (Box 40)
      - Carl Bradley Shipwreck (Box 40)
      - Cruise Assessments (Box 40)
      - Cruise Plans (Box 40)
      - Cruise Reports (Box 40)
      - Insurance (Box 40)
      - Rates and Charge Sheets (Box 40)
      - Schedule (Box 40)
      - Shared Ship Usage (Box 40)
      - Ship's Logs (Box 40)
    - 1998
      - Captain's Post Cruise Reports (Box 40)
      - Cruise Assessments (Box 40)
      - Cruise Plans (Box 40)
      - Cruise Reports (Box 40)
      - Insurance (Box 40)
      - Publicity (Box 40)
      - Rates and Charge Sheets (Box 40)
      - Schedule (Box 40)
      - Ship's Logs (Box 40)
    - 1999
      - Captain's Post Cruise Reports (Box 40)
      - Cruise Assessments (Box 40)
      - Insurance (Box 40)
      - Rates (Box 40)
      - Ship's Logs (Box 40)
    - 2000
      - Cruise Plans (Box 40)
      - Rates and Budget (Box 40)
      - Ship Log Book EEGLE 2000 (Box 40)
      - Schedule (Box 40)
    - 2001
      - Operations Problems (Box 40)
      - Rates (Box 40)
      - Safety Reports (Box 40)
      - Ten-Year Budget Report (Box 40)
      - Time Requests and Ship's Log (Box 40)
    - 2002 Status Reports (Box 40)
- Donald C. Cook Nuclear Power Plant Studies
  Donald C. Cook Nuclear Power Plant Studies, 1967-1983, series documents a number of environmental studies done under contract for the American Electric Power Service Corporation and the Indiana & Michigan Electric Company. The studies were part of the licensing process for the Donald C. Cook nuclear plant in Bridgman, Michigan in compliance with requirements of section 316(a) and 316(b) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act. The field studies began in 1966 and continued through 1982. The records consist primarily of reports prepared by GLRD and other research scientists. The series is divided into five principle subseries: Limnological Studies, Biological Studies, Environmental Impact Statements and Other Reports, Hearings and Regulations, and Ice Studies.
  - Limnological Studies, I-XXI
    (Published as Report No. 44 of the GLRD "Special Reports" series)
    The Limnological Studies subseries consists of reports published as Report No. 44, "Benton Harbor Limnological Studies, I-XXXII", of GLRD's "Special Reports Series." The limnological studies include pre- and post-operational studies to measure the impact of the plant on lake conditions. (The collection does not include all titles in Report No. 44. For a complete listing of "Special Report" titles see the document "Special Report Series" in the Bibliographies subseries. Special Report No. 44 titles present in the collection are listed in the contents list.)
    - I.-General Studies, J. C. Ayers and J. C. K. Huang 1967 (Box 18)
    - II.-Studies of Local Winds and Alongshore Currents, J. C. Ayers. C. F. Powers, and A. Rossman 1967 (Box 18)
    - III-Some Effects of Power Plant Waste Heat on the Ecology of Lake Michigan, J. R. Krezoski 1969 (Box 18)
    - IV.-Cook Plant Operational Studies, N. W. O'Hara, R.F. Anderson, W. L. Yocum, J. C. Ayers 1970 (Box 18)
    - V.-Winter Operations March 1970 (Box 18)
    - VI.-Pontopeoreia Affinis (Crustacea, Amphipoda) as a Monitor of Radionuclides released to Lake Michigan, C. C. Kidd 1970 (Box 18)
    - VII.-Cook Plant Preoperational Studies 1970 J. C. Ayers, R.F. Anderson, H. K. Soo, 1970 (Box 18)
    - VIII.-Winter Operations 1969-1971, J. C. Ayers, N. W. O'Hara, W. L. Yocum 1971 (Box 18)
    - IX.-The Biological Survey of July 1970, J. C. Ayers, W. L. Yocum, H. K. Soo, T. W. Bottrell, S. C. Mosely, L. C. Garcia 1971 (Box 18)
    - X.-Cook Plant Preoperational Studies 1971, J. C. Ayers, H. K. Soo, W. L. Yocum 1972 (Box 18)
    - XI.-Winter Operations 1971-1972, J. C. Ayers, W. L. Yocum 1972 (Box 18)
    - XII.-Studies of the Fish Population Near the Donald C. Cook Nuclear Power Plant, 1972, D. J. Dude, T. W. Bottrell, J. A. Dorr III, T. J. Miller 1973 (Box 18)
    - XIV.-Winter Operations 1972-1973, J. C. Ayers, W. L. Yocum, E. Seibel 1973 (Box 18)
    - XV.-The Biological Surveys of 12 November, 1970, J. C. Ayers, S. C. Mosely, J. C. Roth 1973 (Box 18)
    - XVI.-Psammolittoral Investigation 1972 E. Seibel, J. C. Roth, J. A. Stewart, S. K. Williams, 1973 (Box 18)
    - XVII.-Program of Aquatic Studies Related to Donald C. Cook Nuclear Plant, J. C. Ayers, E. Seibel (eds.) 1973 (Box 18)
    - XVIII.-Effect of a Thermal Discharge on Benthos Populations: Statistical Methods for Assessing the Impact of the Cook Nuclear Plant, E. M. Johnston 1973 (Box 18)
    - XIX.-The Seasonal Biological Surveys of 1971, J. C. Ayers, S. C. Mosely, J. A. Stewart 1974 (Box 18)
    - XX.-Statistical Power of a Proposed Method for Detecting the Effect of Waste Heat on Benthos Populations, E. M. Johnston 1974 (Box 18)
    - XXI.-Bacteria and Phytoplankton of the Seasonal Surveys of 1972, 1973 J. C. Ayers, 1975 (Box 18)
    - XXII.-Underwater Operations in Southeastern Lake Michigan Near the Donald C. Cook Nuclear Power Plant During 1974 J. A. Dorr III and T. J. Miller 1975 (Box 18)
    - XXIII.-Phytoplankton of the Seasonal Surveys of 1974 and 1975 and Initial Pre-vs. Post-operational Comparisons of Cook Nuclear Power Plant, J. C. Ayers, N. V. Southwick, D. G. Robinson 1975 (Box 18)
    - XXIV.-Entrainment of Phytoplankton at the Donald C. Cook Nuclear Power Plant-1975, R. Rossman, N. H. Miller, D. G. Robinson. 1977 (Box 18)
    - XXV.-Phytoplankton of the Seasonal Surveys of 1976 of 1970 and Pre-vs Post-operational Comparisons at Cook Nuclear Plant, J.C. Ayers April 1978 (Box 24)
    - XXVI.-Entrainment of Phytoplankton at the Donald C. Cook Nuclear Plant-1976, R. Rossman, L.D. Damaske, and N.H. Miller. 1979 (Box 24)
    - XXVII.-Phytoplankton of the Seasonal Survey of 1977 and Pre-vs. Post-operational Comparisons at Cook Nuclear Plant, J.C. Ayers and S.J. Wiley. March 1979 (Box 24)
    - XXVIII.-Entrainment of Phytoplankton at the Donald C. Cook Nuclear Plant-1978, W. Chang, R. Rossman, J. Pappas, and W.L. Yocum. May 1981 (Box 24)
    - XXIX.-Phytoplankton of the Seasonal Surveys of 1978 and 1979 and Further Pre-vs. Post-operational Comparisons at Cook Nuclear Plant, J.C. Ayers and Laurie E. Feldt. 1982 (Box 24)
    - XXX.-Entrainment of Phytoplankton at the Donald C. Cook Nuclear Plant-1979, R. Rossman, W. Chang, and James Barres. 1982 (Box 24)
    - XXXI.-Phytoplankton of the Seasonal Surveys of 1980, 1981 and April 1982. Further Pre-vs. Post-operational Comparisons at Cook Nuclear Plant 1983 (Box 24)
    - XXXII.-Entrainment of Phytoplankton at the Donald C. Cook Nuclear Plant, 1980-1982. 1984 (Box 24)
  - Phytoplankton Studies data.
    - Computer printouts (Box 19)
  - Biological Studies, 8 folders
    (principal reports in each folder are listed below)
    - Folder 1
      Biological Studies (8 folders) are a series of reports on the impact of the discharge of heated water from the nuclear plant and its affect on plankton, fish, and waterfowl.
      - "Preliminary Zooplankton Report for the 316A Demonstration for the Cook Nuclear Power Plant", M.S. Evans 1974 (Box 20)
    - Folder 2
      - "Periphyton" (Box 20)
      - "A Rationale as to Why the Once Through Cooling of the Cook Plant Will not Be Harmful to the 'Balanced Indigenous Populations' of the Region" (Box 20)
      - "Effects of Cook Plant on Plankton" (Box 20)
    - Folder 3
      - (Several statements on "heat exchange between open waters of Lake Michigan and 'inshore zones'" (Box 20)
      - "Shoreline Ice Melting at the D.C. Cook" (Box 20)
    - Folder 4
      - Mycrophyton and Waterfowl studies (Box 20)
    - Folder 5-7
      - "Schematized Life Cycles of Fish with Respect to the Cook Plant" (General introduction and reports for each species of fish.) (Box 20)
    - Folder 8
      - "Effects of Climate on Plume Size" (Box 20)
      - "Heat Buildup in Near-Shore Waters" (Box 20)
      - "Total Thermal Load Analysis" (Box 20)
  - Environmental Impact Statement and Other Reports
    The Environmental Impact Statement and Other Reports include the final environmental impact statement, 1973, prepared by the U.S. Atomic Energy Commission; the "Plan of Study and Demonstration Concerning Thermal Discharges at the Donald C. Cook Nuclear Plant," 1975, submitted to the Michigan Water Resources Commission (MWRC); and the "Report on the Impact of Cooling Water Use at the Donald C. Cook Nuclear Plant," 1977, prepared by a law firm for submission to the MWRC.
    The Environmental Technical Specifications define power plant variables, design features, monitoring requirements, and administrative controls necessary to assure a minimized plant impact on the surroundings in accordance with the National Environmental Policy environmental review. The Licensing Hearings subseries, 1974, consists of documents and testimony relating to environmental challenges to the Cook power plant license filed with the Atomic Safety and Licensing Board by a group of interveners collectively known as BPI, including the Sierra Club, West Michigan Environmental Action Council, and the Dunewood Property Owners Association. The documents, some in draft form, are primarily responses to specific points raised in the BPI challenge. Transcripts of the licensing hearings include testimony of John C. Ayers. This does not appear to be a complete transcription of the hearings.
    The Environmental Operating Reports, 1974-1983, are semi-annual reports monitoring the radiological and environmental impact of the Cook nuclear plant. They typically include studies of the plant and animal life at the Cook site, aquatic life, lake temperature and ice studies as well as reports on radiological emissions. The Ice Studies include reports, logs, and photographic slides from a long term study of ice formation in the vicinity of the Cook nuclear plant. (Researchers should also consult the published volume Impact of the Donald C. Cook Nuclear Plant, edited by Ronald Rossman, available in the Bentley Historical Library.)
    - "Environmental Impact Statement," 1973 (Box 20)
    - "Plan of Study and Demonstration Concerning Impact of Water Use at the Cook Nuclear Power Plant," 1977 (Box 20)
    - Environmental Technical Specifications (Box 20)
    - Licensing Hearings 1974
      - BPI Contest, 3 folders (Box 20)
      - Testimony, 3 folders (Box 20)
    - Environmental Operating Reports 1974-1983 (Box 21)
    - Environmental Regulatory Guidelines
      - "Section 31b", 2 folders (Box 22)
      - Thermal and Intake Studies (Box 22)
  - Ice Studies
    - "Shore Ice Structures at Cook Nuclear Plant" (Box 22)
    - Ice Slide Log Books 1972-1982, 6 volumes; 1 folders (Box 25)
    - Ice Slides
      - 1973-1974 (Box 25)
      - 1974-1975 (Box 26)
      - 1975-1976 (Box 27)
      - 1977 (Box 28)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 28)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 29)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 29)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 30)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 31)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 32)
  - Chronological files 1969-1979
    - 1969 Memo, "Some Long-Term Radiological Aspects of the Donald C. Cook Plant," G. Hoyt Whipple (Box 36)
    - 1970
      - Correspondence (Box 36)
      - Lake Michigan Pollution Workshop Conference Excerpts (Box 36)
      - Progress Report: "Effects of Heated Discharges from Nuclear Power Plants on Fish Populations" (Box 36)
    - 1971 Michigan Water Resources Commission Public Hearing (Box 36)
    - 1972 Environmental Protection Agency Releases (Box 36)
    - 1974 Reports (Box 36)
      (includes "Spring and Fall Thermal Bar Development in Lake Superior," "Comments on Calculated Residual Chlorine Concentrations Safe for Fish," and "Study Plan for Thermal Surveys to be Conducted at the D. C. Cook Nuclear Plant, Units 1 and 2)")
    - 1975
      - Lake Michigan Utility Study Group (Box 36)
      - Proposals (Box 36)
      - Report: "Thermal Discharge Plume Monitoring" (Box 36)
    - 1976
      - Proposals and Reports (Box 36)
        (includes "Effects of Intermittent Chlorine Exposure at Different Temperatures to Freshwater Fish" and Section 316(b) Intake Study: Big Rock Nuclear Plant)
      - Publicity (Box 36)
      - Thermal Plume Monitoring Meeting Minutes (Box 36)
      - Zion Nuclear and Waukegan Generating Stations Public Hearings (Box 36)
    - 1977
      - Correspondence (Box 36)
      - Donald C. Cook 316(a) Demonstration Hearing and Commentary (Box 36)
      - Proposal: "Plan of Study for Further Environmental Monitoring at the Donald C. Cook Nuclear Plant" (Box 36)
    - 1978
      - Correspondence (Box 36)
      - Reports (Box 36)
        (includes "Estimates of Equivalent Bottom Area Depletion of Pontoporeia Associated with Cook Nuclear Plant Cooling Water Use", "Five-Year Summary of the Meteorological Impact of a Once-Through Cooling System," "On the Calculation of Production Foregone Due to Entrainment and Impingement of Fishes at the Donald C. Cook Nuclear Plant"
    - 1979
      - Correspondence and Meeting Minutes (Box 36)
      - Proposals (Box 36)
        (includes "Acceptability of the Cook Plant Intake Design" and comments on future monitoring systems)
- Lake Michigan Ice Study circa 1963-1966
  The series Lake Michigan Ice Study, 1963-1966, includes reports and data sheets and charts for a study of ice formation throughout Lake Michigan. It is unclear if this was part of the Coherent Area Study.
  - Reports and Data
    - Final Report (draft) circa 1966 (Box 22)
    - Data Analysis (Box 22)
    - "Growth of Ice on Lake Michigan" (Box 22)
    - Observation Station Reports
      - 1963-1964, 8 folders (Box 22)
      - 1963-1964, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Water Temperature Logs
      - 1963-1964, 9 folders (Box 23)
    - Winter Temperature Report (Box 23)
    - Ice Charts 1965-1966 (Box 23)
- Ayers Research Files
  The Ayers Research Files series includes several reports and articles written by John C. Ayers and files on several research projects. (Some projects may not have been directed by Ayers.) Reports include: "An Effort to Mobilize Inter-University Water-Related Research in the Great Lakes," 1968, "The Eutrophication of Lake Michigan," 1968, and "Exploration of Collateral Data Potentially Applicable to Great Lakes Hydrography and Fisheries," 1958. There is material from a limnological study of Grand Traverse Bay, 1954-1957, a hydrologic survey of the Locust Point power plant, and a transcript of the testimony of Jack L. Hough in the Lake Michigan diversion litigation.
  - Ayers Papers
    - "An Effort to Mobilize Inter-University Water-Related Research in the Great Lakes," 1968 (Box 24)
    - "The Eutrophication of Lake Michigan," 1968 (Box 24)
    - "Exploration of Collateral Data Potentially Applicable to Great Lakes Hydrography and Fisheries," 1958 (Box 24)
  - Research Files
    - The Great Lakes Basin Commission (Box 24)
    - GEK System 1963 (Box 24)
    - Grand River Survey Report 1966 (Box 24)
    - Grand Traverse Bay Study 1954-1957 (Box 24)
      (folders including Naiad and Halcyon cruise log books, and water temperature and plankton data.)
    - Group Contract Project Data 1969-1970 (Box 24)
      (water quality and biological studies off Grand Haven.)
    - Lake Michigan Drift Bottle Research (Box 24)
    - Milwaukee Harbor Study (Box 24)
    - Lake Michigan Diversion Litigation Testimony circa 1964 (Box 24)
    - Locus Point Power Plant Hydrological Survey 1969 (Box 24)
      (printed as GLRD Special Report #45)
    - Research Vessel Design
      - 1963 (Box 24)
      - 1973-1973, 2 folders (Box 24)
- Administration 1971-1998
  - Center for Great Lakes and Aquatic Sciences (CGLAS) Organization 1960-1994
    - Future 1989-1994 (Box 34)
    - General Information (Box 34)
    - Growth 1989-1990 (Box 34)
    - Reorganization of GLMWC to CGLAS 1960-1986 (Box 34)
  - Committees 1976-1997
    - Aquatic Science/Water Sciences Review Committee 1978-1986 (Box 34)
    - Committee Lists (Box 34)
    - Director Search Committee 1987-1989 (Box 34)
    - Equipment Committee 1979-1989 (Box 34)
    - Executive Committee
      - 1976-1983 (Box 34)
      - 1984-1987 (Box 34)
      - 1987-1989 (Box 34)
      - 1990-1997 (Box 34)
    - Great Lakes Advisory Committee 1986 (Box 34)
    - Great Lakes and Marine Waters Center (GLMWC) Review Committee 1984-1985 (Box 34)
    - Great Lakes Study Council Minutes 1990-1991 (Box 34)
    - Library Committee 1983-1991 (Box 34)
    - Management Committee 1976-1977 (Box 34)
    - Publications Committee 1979-1990 (Box 34)
    - Safety Committee 1976-1981 (Box 34)
    - Space Committee 1989-1991 (Box 34)
    - University Coalition for Aquatic Sciences 1989-1990 (Box 34)
    - Vessel Committee 1989 (Box 34)
  - Correspondence 1983-1998
    - Received 1990-1992 (Box 34)
    - Sent 1983-1992 (Box 34)
    - Vice President for Research
      - Charles G. Overberger 1971-1983 (Box 34)
      - Alfred S. Sussman 1983-1985 (Box 34)
      - Linda Wilson 1985-1989 (Box 34)
      - Patricia Whitesell 1989 (Box 34)
      - William C. Kelly 1989-1990 (Box 34)
      - Frederick C. Neidhardt 1998 (Box 34)
  - Great Lakes and Marine Waters Center (GLMWC) Collaboration 1976-1991
    - Administrative Structure 1976 (Box 34)
  - GLMWC 1976-1991 (cont.)
    - General Information (Box 34)
    - Five-Year Plan 1982 (Box 34)
    - Formation 1976-1987 (Box 34)
    - Organizational Change to Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Science 1983 (Box 34)
    - Staff Meeting Minutes 1976-1991 (Box 34)
  - Transfer to Literature, Science and the Arts 1988
    - Reports 1976-1998 (Box 34)
    - Center Overview 1980-1989 (Box 34)
    - Literature, Science and the Arts Year-End Reports, 1991/1992- 1997-1998, 7 folders (Box 34)
    - Research Activities Reports
      - 1976-1979, 4 folders (Box 34)
      - 1980-1992, 13 folders (Box 35)
      - 1993-1998, 6 folders (Box 36)
  - Ten-Year Review (1986-1996) 1996-1997
    - Internal Segment
      - Correspondence 1997 (Box 36)
      - Internal Review Committee 1996 (Box 36)
      - Review of Activities 1996, 2 folders (Box 36)
    - External Segment
      - External Review Committee (contains final report) (Box 36)
      - General Background Information (Box 36)
      - Review of Activities (compiled by CGLAS) (Box 36)
- Grants 1960-1997
  - John M. Armstrong 1976-1980
    - Commercial Port Development and Urban Waterfront Development 1979-1980 (Box 36)
    - Great Lakes Environmental Data and Information Center 1976-1977 (Box 36)
  - Alfred M. Beeton 1977-1985
    - A Cooperative Agreement in Great Lakes Long Term Effects Research 1979-1985 (Box 37)
    - Great Lakes Environmental Research Laboratory 1978-1981 (Box 37)
    - Great Lakes Regional Information Center 1977-1980 (Box 37)
    - Study of the Effect of a Rural Clean Water Project 1981-1983 (Box 37)
    - Study to Determine Factor Affecting the Water Quality of the Huron River-Ford Lake-Belleville Lake System 1978-1980, 2 folders (Box 37)
  - Curtiss O. Davis 1977-1978
    - Lake Michigan Water Quality Evaluation in the Vicinity of Grand Haven, Michigan 1977-1978 (Box 37)
  - Cooperative Institute of Limnology and Ecosystem Research (CILER) 1991-1993
    - Assessment of the Lower Food Web of Saginaw Bay-Import of the Zebra Mussel 1991-1993 (Box 37)
  - Linda S Goad 1977-1995
    - Aquatic Education-An Investment in the Future 1993-1994 (Box 37)